git init - Initialize a new Git repository
git clone - Copy a remote repository to local system
git add - Stage files to prepare for commit
git commit - Save staged changes permanently
git status - Show current status of working directory
git log - Show commit history
git branch - List, create, or delete branches
git checkout - Switch branches
git merge - Merge changes from another branch
git push - Upload local commits to GitHub
